

Kalaiselvan A/L Seakar No 315, Taman Daya Pertama, Sg Choh 48000 Rawang, Selangor

Email: jack3151@yahoo.com/kalaiselvanseakar@gmail.com

|Tel: 01126276952

Objective Statement

To obtain a Technician position that can offer new challenges and provision for potential growth, enable me to attribute my skills, experiences, education and enthusiasm to achieve excellence as well as seeking new career development to widen my knowledge and skills

COMPUTER SKILLS

Microsoft Programs: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Typing

LANGUAGE SKILLS

LANGUAGE	WRITTEN	SPOKEN
Bahasa Malaysia	Good	Good
English	Medium	Medium
Tamil	Good	Good

EXPERIENCES

6 years of experience providing top-notch support and services to the business

- Maxis Communication Berhad- Technician under Network Service OPS Centre (2010 – Present)
- Monitoring Network Element via EMS for MSAN (Multi-Service Access Node), SIMUX, IP DSALM (Internet Protocol Digital Subscriber Line Access Multiplexer), MPLS (Multi-protocol Label Switching), METRO-E (Metro Ethernet) and VSAT (Very small aperture terminal).
- Monitor MSAN, SIMUX, IP DSALM, and MPLS, Metro-E & VSAT alarms via EMS tool (AEM, Mainstreet, U2K, WhatsUp and Gold, Skyedge).
- Troubleshoot to localize the issues. Support and coordinate RNOC/Back Office to resolve the fault.
- Respond to Network Customer Support Team within agreed SLA time frame.
- Create and update/manage trouble tickets for any detected problem.
- Ensure all docket information are capture in activity log
- Managing technical escalation to ensure faults is rectified within agreed SLAs
- Support to enhance improvement on process to develop on existing tools and system.
- Perform Escalation and Notification to keep management and other business units informed during system outages.
- Assist the FO shift leader in producing activity report for KPI calculation.
- Check and certified new network elements to be commissioned in operation environment within agreed KPI. (BIS)
- Perform initial analysis to identify issues follow by restoration if possible (1St line of Support).
- Assist the operation team in process improvement and ongoing development of tools and system.
- Ensure proper work progress, shift handover, data communication, team work spirit.

Job Description

Able to troubleshoot IMS monitoring and basic troubleshooting for PRA link (Fixed line customers)

(The IP Multimedia Subsystem or IP Multimedia Core Network Subsystem (IMS) is an architectural framework for delivering IP multimedia services. Historically, mobile phones have provided voice call services over a switched-circuit-style network, rather than strictly Over an IP packet-switched network.)

- Managing CI(customer impact) based surveillance alarm such as hardware alarms,
 E1 alarm &Opto Alarms
- Opto 1 intruder alarm
- Opto 2 over temperature
- Opto 3 main failure
- Opto 4 high voltage
- Opto 5 low voltage
- Opto 6 rectifier failure
- Opto 7 battery disconnect
- Opto 8 tower light
- Manage Maxis Network monitoring Centre, End to end Fault Management, Fault escalation first level alarm monitoring.
- Monitoring the performance of the network(using U2000/INMS/I2000)

OTHER EXPERIENCES

General Competence

- Good in Microsoft Office
- Good knowledge in written and spoken English
- Good communication skills
- Good in analytic and investigation technique
- Excellent team player

•

Technical Competence

- Good knowledge in maxis Fixed & GSM network.
- Good knowledge about network operation centre processes and interfaces.
- Good knowledge of network implementation / integration processes
- Good PC skill

Additional Info (Training/Seminar)

- Course Title: CSC3300/MRP6600 OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE Start Date: 2013-12-12 End Date: 2013-12-13
- Course Title: ICG9815(OFFLINE CHARGING) OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE Start Date: 2014-05-08 End Date: 2014-05-09

Technical Soft Skills

- Project Management Overview
- Technical writing, presentation and creative problem solving workshop

Technical Competency Training

- Huawei Certified Data communication Associate Program
- Practical SIP(Session Initiation Protocol) Signalling for VoIP(Voice over Internet Protocol)
- Practical RF Engineering
- Next Generation Broadband Network Technologies (NGN)
- Wireless Broadband Technologies (LTE)

EDUCATION

Diploma In Computer Graphic Design Cosmopoint Institute Of Information Technology

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM 2006)

Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Seri Garing (Rawang)

Penilaian Menengah Rendah (PMR 2004)

Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Sungai Choh (Rawang)

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

6 years of experience in Telecommunication with special focus in Network Monitoring and Troubleshooting. Problem-solver and persistently follow-up until issue is resolved.

- Friendly with positive attitude. Proven team player.
- Ambitious and hardworking with commitment to excellence.
- Effective communicator, both written and verbal.
- Highly attentive to detail. Effectively manage multiple tasks simultaneously.
- Good listener with outgoing, friendly demeanor and good sense of humor.
- Always Be Alert By Upgrade Individual Skill Which Needed By the Environments.

Other Info

Possess Own Transport : Yes

Availability

: Immediately

References

1) Name: Puvan

Position: Manager

Company: Maxis Telecommunication

Contact: +60122040476 | Email: kpuvain@maxis.com.my

2) Name: Mathialagan

Position: Network Manager

Company: Maxis Telecommunication

Contact: +60172000195 | Email: smathia@maxis.com.my